# 哈喽大家好 我是王刚
Hello, everyone. I'm Wang Gang.
# 本期视频我跟大家分享一道国宴（菜）
In this video I share with you a state banquet
# 首先我们来准备原材料
First, let's prepare the raw ingredients.
# 准备猪肘子2个从中间切开备用（约4000克）
Prepare 2 pork hocks cut down in the middle (about 4000g)
# 肘子切开之后才能够更好的焯水和煮制
Hocks are better parboiled and cooked after they are cut up.
# 最好准备前肘和后肘各1只
Preferably 1 front hock and 1 back hack.
# 准备黑脚土鸡2只（约3000克）
Prepare 2 black-foot free-range chickens (about 3000g)
# 去除内脏、淋巴、鸡油、爪子（趾甲）之后对半剁开备用
After removing giblets, lymph, fat and claws (toenails), chop them in half.
# 有条件的话可以选择一年以上的黑脚土鸡更佳
Black-foot free-range chickens that are more than a year old are even better, if possible.
# 准备鸭子2只处理干净之后对半剁开备用（约3500克）
Prepare 2 ducks, cleaned and chopped in half (about 3500g).
# 同样选择老鸭汤会更香
Also choose older duck would make the soup more delicious.
# 鸡鸭焯水之前我们先把胸脯肉取下
Before we parboil the chicken and duck, cut off the breast meat.
# 取下的胸脯肉可以作为最后清汤的原料（扫汤）
The removed breast meat can be used as an ingredient for the final soup cleansing.
# 最后我们准备金华火腿1小根（约2000克）
Finally, let's prepare one Jinhua Ham (about 2000 grams).
# 将其剁成小块之后放入盆中
Chop it into chunks and put them in a pot.
# 然后加入适量的热水将其清洗干净
Then add some hot water to rinse.
# 这一步的目的是去除火腿中有异味的油渍（齁鼻的味道）
The purpose of this step is to get rid of the covering oil that have a bad taste.
# 原料最好选择浙江金华火腿
The best choice of ham is Zhejiang Jinhua Ham.
# 肉质紧实甘香且鲜美
The meat is firm, flavorful and delicious.
# 唯一的缺点就是略咸和略柴
The only downside is that it's a bit too salty and the meat fibre is tough.
# 然后再浸泡40分钟去除多余的盐分
Then soak for another 40 minutes to remove excess salt.
# 下一步准备适量的大葱切成长段
Next prepare some spring onions cut into long pieces.
# 准备生姜150克拍散备用
Prepare 150 grams of ginger and crush them.
# 下一步开始原料初加工
The next step is to start preliminary processing of raw ingredients.
# 首先我们将处理好的鸡鸭肘子下锅
First, put the chicken, duck and hock in a pot.
# 锅中加入没过原材料的清水
Add water to the pot that covered the ingredients.
# 然后开大火将其焯水去除多余的血水
Then parboil them over high heat to remove the excess blood.
# 中途加入泡好的火腿块
Add the soaked ham chunks halfway through.
# 大火烧开之后撇去浮沫
Skim off the foam after it boiled.
# 焯好水之后将所有原材料捞出放入盆中
After parboil, remove all the ingredients into a bowl.
# 再加入适量的清水将原材料仔细清洗干净备用
Add some water and clean the ingredients carefully.
# 原料清洗干净之后下一步开始“煮开水”
Once the ingredients are clean, the next step is to "boil the Kaishui".
# 首先我们准备50厘米直径节能锅一个
First, let's prepare a 50 cm diameter energy-saving pot.
# 锅底放入蒸格防止肘子糊底
Put steamer grids in the bottom of the pan to prevent the hocks from sticking.
# 然后将所有原材料均匀的放入锅中
Then place all the ingredients evenly in the pot.
# 再加入清水30公斤
Then add 30 kg of water.
# 最后加入切好的姜葱
Finally, add the chopped ginger and spring onions.
# 开大火烧开之后转小火熬煮4个小时
Bring to a boil over high heat, then lower the heat and simmer for 4 hours.
# 同学们浓汤开大火
If you want a thick soup then use high heat.
# 清汤开小火
If you want a clear soup then use low heat.
# 所以我们必须将火力保持在微开的状态
That's why we need to keep our heat at a low level.
# 熬制1个小时之后将大葱捞出防止发酸
After simmering for 1 hour, drain the spring onions to prevent souring.
# 然后将漂浮的“黄油”撇出不用
Then skim off the floating "yellow oil".
# 锅中的“黄油”主要是从火腿中析出
The "yellow oil" is extracted mainly from the ham.
# 然后继续熬煮剩余的3个小时
Then continue to simmer for the remaining 3 hours.
# 中途我们来准备扫汤的辅料
In the middle of the process, let's prepare the ingredients for cleansing the soup.
# 首先我们将准备好的鸡鸭脯肉去除多余的肥油和筋膜
First, remove excess fat and sinew from the chicken and duck breasts.
# 然后分开切成小条备用
Then cut it into small strips.
# 再准备猪里（外）脊肉800克切成小块备用
Also prepare 800 grams of pork loin, cut into small pieces.
# 然后将所有的扫汤原料分别的放入料理机中
Then use food processor to blending all the ingredients separately.
# 再加入其四倍的清水搅打成肉蓉倒出备用
Add four times as much water and make into a puree.
# 同学们扫汤的原料是搅得越细越好
The finer the meat puree the better.
# 这样在清汤的时候才能够将更多的杂质清除
Finer puree will remove more of the impurities during the soup cleansing.
# 让汤更加的清澈透明
It makes the soup clearer and more transparent.
# 原汤熬制4个小时之后将所有的原材料捞出
After 4 hours of simmering, remove all the ingredients from the pot.
# 同学们最好是用纱布过滤一遍去除所有的细渣
Strain the soup through a filter cloth to remove all the fine residue.
# 然后待原汤稍微冷却至60度
Then let the "Kaishui" stock cool slightly to 60 degrees.
# 冷却的目的是方便下一步扫汤
The purpose of cooling is to make it easier to clean the soup in the next step.
# 原汤冷却之后先加入处理好的鸭脯肉
After the stock has cooled, add the processed duck breasts.
# 然后转小火煮20分钟左右
Then use low heat and cook for about 20 minutes.
# 在这个过程中鸭肉蓉受热膨胀
In the process, the duck puree expands.
# 肉蓉熟透之后会吸收汤里面的杂质浮出水面
When the puree meat is cooked, it will absorb the impurities in the soup and rise to the surface.
# 川菜餐饮行业中称之为清汤或者扫汤
In the Sichuan cuisine, this process is called cleaning or sweeping soup.
# 扫汤的原材料可以用鸡、鸭、鱼、猪肉
Chicken, duck, fish and pork can be used as ingredients for cleaning soup.
# 从肉的颜色深到浅开始扫汤
Clean the soup from dark to light color of meat.
# 所以我们的排序分别是鸭脯肉、猪肉、鸡脯肉
So our order is duck breasts, pork, and chicken breasts.
# 同样每次都需要用纱布过滤肉蓉
You also need to strain the puree meat through filter cloth every time.
# 经过3次以上的扫汤之后再将其全部过滤沉淀备用
After 3 or more cleansing of the soup, strain it all for later use.
# 下一步我们开始准备白菜
Next let's start preparing the cabbage.
# 准备白菜一颗去除外围的绿色部分
Prepare one cabbage to remove the outer green parts
# 只取中间黄色菜叶或者白菜芯即可
Just use the middle yellow leaf or cabbage core.
# 首先我们在锅中加入适量的清水和食用盐
First, add some water and salt to the wok.
# 大火烧开之后加入黄色部分的白菜叶焯水至断生
Bring the water to boil over high heat, then add the yellow part of the cabbage leaves and blanch until they half cook.
# 菜叶断生之后捞出放入冰水中冷却攥干水分
When the leaves are half cooked, remove them from the water and cool them in ice water.
# 这一步的目的是去除白菜叶的异味并保持口感
The purpose of this step is to remove the odor and preserve the taste of the cabbage leaves.
# 攥干水分之后摆入盘中
Squeeze the water and arrange on a plate.
# 加入沉淀好的“开水”（原汤）
Adding the clear "Kaishui" (stock soup)
# 然后封上保鲜膜放入蒸锅
Then cover with plastic wrap and place in a steamer.
# 水开之后计算时间蒸5分钟
Steam for 5 minutes after boiling.
# 5分钟之后取出菜盘
Remove the tray after five minutes.
# 夹出白菜重新摆入盘中
Remove the cabbage and rearrange on a plate.
# 再次放入“开水”之后放上1颗枸杞作为点缀即可上菜
Add the "Kaishui" again and garnish with 1 goji berry and serve.
# 同学们注意
Attention,
# 酒店出品会将白菜从中间切开
The high end restaurant will cut the cabbage down the middle.
# 取下端煮熟之后用剪刀将叶子剪成荷花形状
Take the bottom end and cook it, then use scissors to cut the leaves into lotus shapes.
# 下面开始成品展示
Let's start with the finished product.
# 普通的摆盘方式
Common way to set the plate
# 白菜叶直接摆盘淋上“开水”
Cabbage leaves directly on the plate and pour in "Kaishui"
# 此做法简单直接
This approach is straightforward.
# 下一个为酒店摆盘方式
The next one is the high end plating.
# 收芯的莲花冲入“开水”散开
Pour in "Kaishui" on the lotus flowers to blossom.
# 一道汤清味美的开水白菜就制作完成
A delicious “Kaishui Baicai” is ready.
# 下面开始技术总结
Let's start the technical summary.
# 第一
First,
# 传统开水白菜的原材料是整鸡、整鸭、整肘子、金华火腿
Traditional "Kaishui" stock is made from whole chicken, whole duck, whole pig hock, and Zhejiang Jinhua ham.
# 全部放入锅中焯水后洗干净重新加入清水
Parboil all in a pot of water and rinse to re-add water.
# 开小火吊4至6小时
Simmer on low heat for 4 to 6 hours.
# 第二
Second,
# 原汤“开水”不需要添加任何调味品
The stock soup "Kaishui" does not require any additional seasoning.
# 其中火腿调咸味
Where the ham is for salty flavor.
# 鸡鸭调鲜香味
Chicken and Duck are for umami flavor.
# 肘子增香调浓稠
The pig hock is for thickening and flavoring.
# 第三
Third,
# 扫汤的原料最好用料理机打碎打细
The ingredients for the soup cleansing are best pureed in a food processor.
# 传统刀剁比较慢
Traditional knives are slower.
# 就算快刀剁最少也需要30分钟以上
Even a quick chop will take at least 30 minutes or more.
# 第四
Fourth,
# 白菜芯量少
If you feel there is not much cabbage core,
# 也可以用娃娃菜代替
You can also use baby napa cabbage instead.
# 第五
Fifth,
# 扫汤的原材料下锅有明确的顺序
There is a clear order of the ingredients for the soup cleansing.
# 只需要将原料颜色从深到浅下锅即可
You just need to follow the color the ingredients from dark to light.
# 第六
Sixthly,
# 下方为所有原料种类、比例、单价、实际损耗清单
The following is a list of all raw material types, ratios, unit prices, and actual consumption.